https://savingplaces.org/privacy-policy#.XrQewGhKg2w

Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy of the National Trust for Historic Preservation
Changes in the Privacy Policy
SCOPE OF THE PRIVACY POLICYThis Privacy Policy applies to the websites (collectively, the “Websites”) that are owned and operated by the National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States, its subsidiaries, affiliates and historic sites that are owned and operated by the National Trust, including, but not limited to, the National Trust Community Investment Corporation (“NTCIC”); National Trust Tours, LLC; National Trust Insurance Services, LLC; National Main Street Center, Inc.; and the following historic sites: Chesterwood, Farnsworth House, Frank Lloyd Wright’s Pope Leighey House, Lyndhurst, Philip Johnson Glass House, Shadows-on-the-Teche, Woodlawn, and the Woodrow Wilson House (collectively, the “National Trust”). This Privacy Policy states the National Trust's policy with regard to the personal identifiable information you provide.
The National Trust is committed to honoring the privacy preferences of members of the public that visit our Websites. Our intention through these Websites is to supply information that will help people learn about, experience and work to save historic places, and build better communities. In the course of providing these online services, information may be exchanged between the National Trust, servers, online users and their browsers. In order to access certain materials or services on the Websites, you may be asked to provide your name, address, phone number and/or other information. It is your decision to provide this information. We will only use this information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please be advised that you may opt-out of receiving certain information from the National Trust as provided herein. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Websites.
The National Trust’s Terms of Use also govern the use of the Websites.
back to top
PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTION
Personal Information Collected
The National Trust has a strong commitment to internet privacy. We provide choices to the consumer in deciding when and how to provide different categories of "personally identifiable information" (e.g., data that may be used to identify, contact or locate a person such as name, physical address, e-mail address and phone number and information you provide to help customize your web experience). In general, when you visit our Websites and access information, we do not require you to register or provide personal identifiable information to us. However, there are occasions when we will ask for additional information. For example, you may be required to register your name and e-mail address or other necessary information in order to enter certain member-only areas of the Websites such as for Forum and Partners. You may also be required to register your name and e-mail address and provide other information if you wish to receive e-newsletters, event information, participate in special initiatives or in surveys or contests. It is your choice to provide such information, and you may opt-out from receiving any of this type of information in the future.
Personally identifiable information, such as your name, physical address, e-mail address, phone number and credit card information will be collected if you wish to become a member of the National Trust online, make purchases online, receive e-newsletters, or make online donations. Please be advised that we will never share your credit card information. Nor will we ever share your email address or other personal identifiable information provided unless otherwise authorized by you or as stated in this Privacy Policy.
Internet Protocol and Cookies
We may keep track of your interactions with our Websites and our services to offer a more personalized experience through your Internet Protocol address or through the use of “Cookies” and web analytics services.
An Internet Protocol (IP) address is associated with the portal through which you enter the internet, like your internet service provider (ISP). Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our visitors visit various parts of our Websites. We may also combine this information with personally identifiable information, e.g., your name and address that you have provided to us and/or with other information that is publicly available or that we receive from other reputable sources in order to make our Websites and communications more targeted to your interests.
"Cookies" are small files sent from a web server to your computer through your browser program that permit the computer to help customize your experience with our Websites. The National Trust uses cookies to measure visitation to the National Trust’s Websites, including repeat visitors and to perform certain functions such as order processing, registrations, and advertising. Cookies may be used to store some history about the parts of our Websites that you have visited to help you navigate our Websites more easily or to alert you to related pages on our Websites that may interest you. The National Trust does not use cookies to obtain information about other Websites that you may have visited. The National Trust may also use web analytics services and conversion tracking, which use cookies and other means to collect and analyze data. These services, however, do not collect personal identifiable information. For more information about cookies, visit www.cookiecentral.com.
Webpage Sharing and e-Cards
If a user elects to share pages from our Websites with friends, colleagues or on social media sites or send e-Cards, we ask for the recipient’s name and e-mail address. The National Trust will automatically send the recipient a one-time message inviting them to visit a website. The National Trust uses the recipient's information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail, and the recipient information is not retained.
Personally Identifiable Information Contained in User Content
Some sections of our Websites may allow users to post or transmit messages, comments, screen names, computer files and other materials. We encourage your thoughts, stories, photos, but be advised that any content you submit to the Websites will not be returned to you and may be used by the National Trust in any manner we see fit, including reprinting it in full or in modified version on our Websites or elsewhere or using elements of it on our Websites. You will not be entitled to any remuneration for any use of your content by the National Trust.
You are solely responsible for the contents of your transmission through our Websites. The National Trust is not obligated to monitor such transmissions, and therefore cannot be responsible for any personally identifiable information or other information that may be contained in such transmissions. You agree not to transmit through the Websites any unlawful, harassing, libelous, abusive, threatening, or harmful material of any kind or nature.
Please review the National Trust’s Terms of Use for more information regarding user content posted to the Websites.
back to top
USE OF INFORMATION AND PRIVACY CHOICESUse of Personal Information
If you provide the National Trust with your personal identifiable information, we will not share that information with other organizations, unless you have otherwise authorized us to do so or as stated in this Privacy Policy.
If you provide your personal identifiable information on a public forum (e.g. a blog) the National Trust is not responsible for monitoring these transmissions and cannot be responsible for any personally identifiable information contained in such transmissions. Please review the National Trust’s Terms of Use for more information. If you wish to be removed from one of our e-mail lists or from receiving information from the National Trust, you may opt-out at any time.
Use of Membership Information
On a selective basis, members of the National Trust may be selected to receive information via postal mail from other non-profit organizations, including state and local preservation organizations and occasionally for-profit organizations that we think may be of interest to you. You have the right to opt-out of these mailings.
Links to Third Party Websites
We provide many links to third party websites existing outside of the National Trust. Since we do not control the content or functionality of these websites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on those third party websites. Any link from www.preservationnation.org, www.savingplaces.org or another National Trust website to a third party website does not denote an affiliation with the website or an endorsement of its viewpoint(s) or mission(s). Please review the National Trust’s Terms of Use for more information.
Subsidiaries, Affiliates and National Trust Historic Sites
The National Trust has a number of subsidiaries, affiliates and historic sites that offer a wide range of products and services. We may share your personal identifiable information with the National Trust’s subsidiaries, affiliates and historic sites to inform you of the various product and service offerings in which you might be interested unless you opt-out of receiving such information. Most of the subsidiaries, affiliates and historic sites owned and operated by the National Trust are subject to the same opt-out rights that apply to use of personally identifiable information by the National Trust. The National Trust’s list of subsidiaries, affiliates, and historic sites includes the following:
National Trust Historic Sites
Stewardship Historic Sites (owned and operated by the National Trust) include: Chesterwood, Cooper Molera Adobe, Farnsworth House, Frank Lloyd Wright’s Pope Leighey House, Lyndhurst, Philip Johnson Glass House, Shadows-on-the-Teche, Woodlawn, and Woodrow Wilson House
Co-Stewardship Historic Sites (operated and/or owned by other non-profit organizations) include: Acoma Sky City, African Meeting House, African Meeting House and Abiel Smith School, Belle Grove, Brucemore, Cliveden, Decatur House, Drayton Hall, Filoli, Gaylord Building, Hotel de Paris Museum, James Madison’s Montpelier, Kykuit, Lower East Side Tenement Museum, Oatlands, President Lincoln’s Cottage (leased by National Trust), Touro Synagogue, and Villa Finale.
National Trust Community Investment Corporation (“NTCIC”)
National Trust Insurance Services, LLC
National Trust Tours, LLC
National Main Street Center, Inc.
The Co-Stewardship Historic Sites, affiliates, and subsidiaries may have and operate their own websites. The National Trust does not control the privacy practices or terms of use of those entities’ websites; therefore, you should review their practices before you choose to access their products or services. If, at a later date, you decide to opt-out of receiving information from those entities, you will need to contact them directly.
Co-Branded Partners
From time to time, the National Trust may offer certain promotions, programs or activities on our Websites or on websites hosted or managed by the National Trust that are co-sponsored or co-branded by non-profit and/or for-profit partners, such as purchasing products or services offered by our partners, or electing to participate in advocacy campaigns, contests, sweepstakes, games or other programs sponsored in whole or in part by our partners, which will be subject to their own terms of use. At the time of engagement, you will be offered an opportunity to choose to authorize the National Trust to share your information with our partners so you may receive information from the partners. We do not control the privacy practices or terms of use of our co-branded partners; therefore, you should review their privacy practices before you choose to access their products or services. You are entitled to opt-out from receiving any resulting information from the National Trust as set forth in this Privacy Policy at any time. However, if at a later date, you decide to opt-out of receiving information from our partners, you will need to contact the partners directly.
Licensees
We may share your personally identifiable information (e.g. name and address) with third parties that offer products or services under or in association with brand names of the National Trust. A licensee is one whose products or services are offered to you with our name. These licensees are restricted by contract to use your information solely for purposes of marketing or promotional materials related to National Trust products or services. You are entitled to opt-out from receiving this information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you choose to access purchases through one of our licensees, they may in some cases collect your personal identifiable information subject to their own privacy policies. We do not control the privacy practices of our licensees; therefore, you should review their privacy practices before you choose to access their products or services, and you will need to contact the licensees directly to opt-out of receiving information from them.
Third Party Advertising
We use third party advertising companies to service ads when you visit our Websites. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to the Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here.
Other Disclosures
The National Trust will share personal identifiable information with third parties if we have a good-faith belief that disclosing the information is reasonably necessary to:
Meet applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request;
Enforce the National Trust’s Terms of Use;
Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; and/or
Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of the National Trust as required or permitted by law.
back to top
SECURITY OF YOUR CREDIT CARD INFORMATIONAll information provided to the National Trust is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on secure portions of our Websites that are only accessible by certain qualified employees of the National Trust. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information.
If you do not wish to use our online payment services, payments and donations may be made by contacting our 24-hour call center at 1-800-315-NTHP (6847).
Some of the National Trust Stewardship Historic Sites’ websites include links to online stores or for ticket sales that are operated by third party companies. You should review the credit card security information and the privacy policies of those third party companies before making a purchase.
back to top
COMPLIANCE WITH FEDERAL LAWSChildren's Privacy Policy
None of the Websites covered by this Privacy Policy knowingly collect personal identifiable information from children under the age of 13. The Websites are not directed to, nor do they have knowledge of, visitors less than 13 years of age. We are committed to protecting children's privacy, and we will monitor our Websites and their users to make sure that their privacy is protected. If we discover that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with any personal identifiable information, we will delete that information from our systems. We are unable to reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate the requests from children under the age of 13 on their behalf. If we begin marketing to children on-line and we are aware that those children are under the age of 13, the National Trust will take steps to fully comply with the Children's Advertising Review Unit (CARU) and the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). To learn more about both of these programs, see www.coppa.org.
Spam
The National Trust complies fully with the Controlling the Assault on Non-Solicited Pornography and Marketing Act of 2003 (CAN-SPAM Act). To this end, the National Trust: ALWAYS provides recipients of e-mail marketing and e-newsletters a clear mechanism to opt-out of receiving information in the future and honors any such requests promptly. ALWAYS provides accurate header and subject line information prior to sending any e-mails. The National Trust commits to sending only e-mails with specific subject lines and a clear delineation from whom the e-mail was sent. ALWAYS provides the National Trust's physical address within the body of all of our e-mail messages.
back to top
QUESTIONS; OPT-OUT
The National Trust welcomes comments or questions on this Privacy Policy. We are dedicated to protecting your personal identifiable information and will make every reasonable effort to keep that information secure. If you have any questions or wish to opt-out, please contact us via email, phone or mail at:
Constituent Services Department National Trust for Historic Preservation 2600 Virginia Avenue NW, Suite 1100 Washington, DC 20037
members@savingplaces.org 1-800-315-NTHP (6847)
Opt-out requests should include “Opt-Out” in the e-mail or letter subject line. Any information you provide to us is covered by this Privacy Policy.
UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION
You can help the National Trust ensure the accuracy of your information. If you have any changes to your physical address, title, e-mail address, name, or phone number, please:
Update your constituent profile online if you are already registered with the National Trust;
Submit an address change request via email if you are not already registered;
Call us at 1-800-315-NTHP (6847); or
Write the Constituent Services Department at the address above.
CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY POLICYWe may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personally identifiable information will be posted on-line. You are bound by such revisions and should therefore visit the page to review the current terms from time to time. Your continued use of the Websites constitutes an affirmative acknowledgement by you of the terms and modifications and your agreement to abide and be bound by the terms as modified.
back to top
Join us in protecting and restoring places where significant African American history happened.
Learn More
Close
Double Your Impact to Save the Irreplaceable
Through December 31, a generous member will match your gift, dollar-for-dollar, up to $100,000. Please give today to save America’s historic places!
